Kyle Haugen

124 Bloomfield Way, Folsom, California 95630 (916) 337-4286 devkdhaugen@gmail.com

WEB LINKS

Personal Website: https://pandabomb-roa.github.io/

Github: https://github.com/PANDABOMB-RoA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dev-kyle-haugen/

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Jan. 2021 – Present Portland, OR

Software Developer, The Tech Academy

- Developed web applications using HTML, Javascript, CSS and C#.
- Participated in Agility sprints, completing stories and attending daily stand up meetings.

Mar. 2020 - Present

GML2 coder | Mechanical Design | Project Leader, Seeds of Aether

- Created playable video game characters for Seeds of Aether computer game.
- Self taught Game Maker Language 2.0.
- Coordinated project assignments between team mates to complete projects of quality and in a timely manner.
- Communicated with user base to make product as appealing as possible.

Mar. 2013 – Mar. 2020 Folsom, California

Bartender | Trainer, Olive Garden

- Catered to guest, serving food and drinks with accuracy, quality and in a timely manner.
- Juggle an ever changing list of priorities from guest request
- Assist and guide other team members to ensure quality service throughout the establishment.

SKILLS

Javascript

MVC Entity

Project Management	
Game Maker Language 2.0	
SQL Data Management	
HTML	
Concept Design	
.Net and C#	

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Mathematically educated and creative mind. Driven to create novel and captivating user experiences. Self taught coding during the 2020 pandemic and then pursued education and certification through The Tech Academy boot camp program. Works well in tandem with others and willing to lead. Has an unending thirst to learn and improve.

EDUCATION

Jul. 2021	Computer Science
	The Tech Academy - Portland, Oregon
Dec. 2020	Associate of Science: Mathematics
	Sacramento State University of California - Sacramento, California
Jun. 2014	Associate of Science: Psychology
	Folsom Lake College - Folsom, California